Contact

9493108534 (Mobile) ryangriego@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ryangriego-2134a340 (LinkedIn) ryangriego.com (Portfolio) github.com/ryan-griego/ (Other)

Top Skills

DigitalOcean
Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Front-End Development

Ryan Griego

Software Developer | React | Vue | Next.js | TypeScript | JavaScript | Python

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

Summary

Hi, I'm Ryan Griego and I'm a software developer who brings a number of experiences working with both small and medium-sized businesses including e-commerce and educational organizations in the area of developing web solutions, deploying email marketing campaigns and handling multiple technical aspects of online marketing while leveraging various digital media technologies.

After having completed my degree in Visual Communication Design, I learned front-end web development by tinkering with my own projects and enrolling in classes to continue furthering my knowledge and application of technical skills. My continuous pursuit of understanding all aspects of web/application design & development allows me to provide solutions to many industries.

Front-end: JavaScript, React, Next.js, Vue, Nuxt.js, TypeScript,

HTML5, CSS3

Back-end: PHP, Node.js, Express

Database: PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB

Tools: Git, Docker, Webpack

Email: ryangriego@gmail.com Github: github.com/ryan-griego

Portfolio: ryangriego.com Blog: ryangriego.com/blog

Experience

Lake Forest Web Designs
Developer
February 2022 - Present (3 years 8 months)
Lake Forest, California, United States

 Builds and maintains websites for small businesses, making sites that are user-friendly and fully responsive. • Design marketing materials, manage email campaigns, and set up business emails for clients.

Integrated Google Maps and other APIs to enhance site functionality and user engagement.

- Migrated hosting services from AWS to DigitalOcean, reducing hosting costs by 75% by using containerization and server optimization.
- Deployed and managed Docker containers to ensure fast, and reliable website/application launches.

Provide technical support, troubleshooting issues for clients, and keeping sites running.

LifeMD (Formerly Conversion Labs)
Associate Full Stack Engineer
February 2021 - May 2023 (2 years 4 months)

- Optimized internal reporting, back-end processes, and user interfaces using JavaScript, Vue.js, PHP, MySQL, and AWS, enhancing application performance.
- Developed and deployed a prescription generation system with PHP and a call monitoring system using JavaScript and Vue.js, significantly enhancing data handling and visualization.
- Instituted a Cron job with Bash and AWS S3 to archive patient recordings, improving data security and compliance.

Eagle Industrial Group, Inc.
Front-end Web Developer
March 2018 - July 2020 (2 years 5 months)
Lake Forest, California

- Engineered three ecommerce platforms using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, WordPress, Bootstrap, and WooCommerce, increasing transaction completion rate.
- Implemented an automated email marketing campaign with Mailchimp and Adobe Photoshop, boosting inquiry rates by 200-300 monthly.
- Created over 20 SEO-optimized blog articles and redesigned sales materials, enhancing online visibility and sales material effectiveness.

Eight Horses Front-end Web Developer September 2017 - February 2018 (6 months) Irvine, California Collaborated to produce web content and emails, enhancing client engagement and website visibility using WordPress, Shopify, and BigCommerce.

scuba.com Webmaster July 2014 - July 2016 (2 years 1 month) Irvine, CA

 Saved management 3 hours per week by enhancing promotional email campaigns and developing marketing materials, increasing site traffic and productivity.

San Francisco State University Graphic Designer August 2012 - May 2013 (10 months)

 Designed posters, brochures, logos and social media ads for various events and departments under the Dean of Students at San Francisco State University

Education

LearningFuze

Full Stack Web Development · (2019 - 2020)

San Francisco State University

Bachelor's of Science, Visual Communication Design · (2011 - 2013)

Saddleback College

Graphic Design · (2007 - 2011)